FEMALE NEWSREADER: ...Royal Dutch Shell
recently saying it would lay off
10,000 workers as it mergers with BG Group,
but that it will at least maintain
its payout this year.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
BP, Exxon Mobil, Conoco,
Phillips, and Chevron...
- It's open.
- ...have all taken similar steps to...
(DOOR OPENING)
MIKE REGAN: Hey, Patrick, good to see you.
- PATRICK: Good to see you.
- Thanks, sit down.
Help yourself.
I'm grand, thanks, grand.
So, I spoke to Michael Arndt, SEC compliance.
He says you're four to three
at the moment, it looks good.
All right, anyone with him?
PATRICK: Yeah, all except Patricia Warren.
- Well, that's a pity.
- PATRICK: No, no, he says she's, you know...
flexible.
Just needs a little nudge, right direction.
She's yours.
It's a done deal.
You've got the SEC in your pocket, Mike.
Thanks a million.
(NEWS INTRO MUSIC PLAYING)
FEMALE NEWSREADER:
Self-made aviation tycoon...
...Mike Regan, is taking his private
jet business to an even higher altitude.
The latest development,
Regan is taking his company public.
So will investors bite?
KAI RYSSDAL: This is Marketplace,
I'm Kai Ryssdal.
Here's one for you, Mike Regan, a 52-year
old owner of the private jet business
that bears his name is about
to take his company public.
He's launching an app
for millionaires, I suppose,
that'll let 'em book a jet the same way
you and I would book an Uber.
Is it gonna work? I have no idea.
He needs cash and some
deep-pocketed investors,
but they are his regular customers.
Not to be left out, Regan needs
the SEC to sign off on that IPO.
MALE NEWSREADER: On to aviation news now.
Private jet maverick,
Michael Regan, is set to go before
the U.S. Securities and
Exchange Commission next week.
He's seeking the green light to bring
his private aviation company public.
Will it work? The SEC will decide soon.
Frequently sought, leaving...
- Hey.
- Hi, Rusty.
How'd it go?
Yeah, all's good, all's good.
Aren't you gonna head to school today?
Mm-hm.
Just one more cup before I face the kids.
(KISSING) Morning, sunshine.
Hey.
Hey, whatever happened
to "Good morning, Daddy"?
I'm not a little girl anymore.
Oh, no? Who told you that?
(MACHINE BEEPING AND WHIRRING)
(TAPPING MACHINE)
Okay, can I just get a coffee pot for myself?
Just my own coffee pot? That'd be great.
- (MACHINE BEEPING)
- (LIQUID SLOSHING)
- (ROSE LAUGHING)
- Would you look at that?
You're an amazing woman.
- ROSE: It's easy.
- Hey, can I get a new phone?
Oh, sure. What color would you like?
Really? Because Lance has the...
- Hilarious.
- (CAR HORN HONKING)
All right, Lance is here, I gotta go.
- Mm-mm, finish your breakfast.
- No, I got school, I gotta go.
Finish your breakfast.
Hey!
Dad, can you have someone fix the wifi?
- It's crazy slow.
- (MIKE SIGHING)
That is not okay.
She's 17.
I'm gonna grab a shower.
Then I'm gonna jump straight into this thing.
I gotta go, but I'll kiss you,
forever and a day.
(ROSE CHUCKLING)
See ya.
MALE NEWSREADER: It's a real rags-to-riches
story and investors, they want in on this.
FEMALE NEWSREADER:
Well, you've said that if the SEC
approves the initial public offering,
the company is going to be valued
in the hundreds of millions of dollars.
How will Regan generate earnings?
MALE NEWSREADER:
Well, there's an app for that.
Regan has what I think is a genius...
- (SHOWER RUNNING)
- (MACHINE BEEPING)
MIKE: Good morning, everyone.
My name is Mike Regan. I own this company.
Now, I know you're all here
to listen to me talk about
this brilliant app we've invented.
But, right now,
I want to talk about flying.
Frank, you took your first solo flight at 16,
single-engine ticket at 17, am I right?
Alan, certified at multi's at 22,
and jets at 28.
And then we have Lizzy here,
the first female G550 driver.
We love to fly, it's the freedom of it all.
It changes you.
You're not fixed on the ground
like some rock.
You're as free as you'll ever be.
But it's expensive, isn't it?
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
I'm gonna take this business
and blow it up and invent a new one.
Let me show you the future.
(APPLAUDING)
(BEEPING)
WOMAN: Private aviation.
What if it could be made even more efficient?
What if your investment
could be put to work for you?
What if there was a way
to make your jet work for you?
Now, there is.
Introducing the Omni Jet
mobile app from Regan Aviation.
(APPLAUDING)
Omni tracks over 15,000 private
and corporate jet aircraft
in real time, and matches your needs
with available aircraft
every second of ev-day...
(BUZZING AND CRACKING)
(WHISPERING) Fuck.
Joan?
I'll just be a moment.
Best laid plans.
It's too early in the morning
for cocktails, I think.
So, not the start I was hoping for.
- (BEEPING)
- Andy!
I know, I'm working it at this end.
Grab the temp guy.
I need you.
ED: I'm sorry it's taking so long, Mr. Regan.
Technology, eh?
ED: Yeah.
There you go, you're back up.
Well, now, that was fun.
- (MIKE CHUCKLING)
- (AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Good, very good.
Very, very, very good.
Now, let's talk about Omni.
How do you think it went?
Home run...
despite the glitch.
I hope so, Joan.
We need this.
Need it?
Need it.
Grab Sully, will you?
We need to go over the IPO.
Yeah.
MIKE: All right, Dave, thank you.
Good night, good work, travel safe.
DAVE: Goodnight, Mike.
- MIKE: Hey.
- Sorry. I'm sorry, Mr. Regan.
Hey, you're the I.T. guy, right?
- Yeah, that's right, Ed Porter.
- Yeah, Mike Regan.
You really saved my ass
in there today, thanks.
- ED: Yeah, yeah.
- You're new?
Yeah, just a temp.
Okay, well, we'll try and fix that.
- Okay? See you tomorrow.
- ED: Thanks.
Hey, listen, can I ask you something?
Are you doing anything over the weekend?
No, I'm pretty free.
Good, maybe you can come over to our
house, have a look at our internet?
My daughter's complaining about it.
- Would that be okay?
- Not a problem.
Okay, Joan'll give you the address tomorrow.
Good night...
- Ed.
- (LAUGHING)
Ed, goodnight, good man.
- ROSE: Hello?
- ED: Err, Ed Porter, ma'am.
ROSE: I'm sorry, who?
Err... Ed Porter, I'm the I.T. guy.
ROSE: Oh, yeah, come on... Come in, come in.
Sorry, sweetie, come on up.
Wow, she's beautiful.
Hey, climb in.
Sit yourself down.
New car smell.
I feel like a kid with a new toy.
I can't stop playing with it.
Check out this NAV system.
- (BEEPING)
- You see that?
It's like a bloody Gulfstream.
Yeah, not bad.
Not bad? What are you saying?
I mean, it's great, it's top of the line...
for civilian stuff.
So you got something better then?
Oh, yeah. I've got something way better.
You know, but it's... it's third party.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Should we be doing this?
Eh...
No.
Come on, Mike, you're a pilot, this is DC.
You know the military spec
stuff that's out there.
Huh.
I mean, this talks to you,
like the civilian stuff.
Tells you which turns to take, all that.
But it's a mil-spec network.
USG satellite coverage.
You know, faster real time, never glitches.
You'll love it.
All right, well,
just don't void the warranty.
(CHUCKLING)
WOMAN: System upgraded.
- ED: Yeah, buddy.
- Nice one.
All right.
Yeah. You're welcome.
ED: I've gotta say, Mike,
you've got a lot of old stuff here
for a new-build, seriously.
MIKE: Where the hell were you when
my tech team was building the app?
I was working for someone else.
Say, can I get your wi-fi password?
MIKE: It's just reganhome1.
- ED: One word?
- MIKE: Yeah.
Who were you working for?
ED: The government.
Really?
Is that where you learned your stuff?
Mostly. I was recruited
straight out of college.
MIKE: No shit. To do what?
- Oh, signals, intel stuff.
- Really?
What do you mean?
I'm not really supposed to talk about it.
Got it.
Hey, you know that the smart panels
in your home
have got built-in cameras, right?
Yeah, I had 'em disabled.
I like my privacy.
Privacy's over, Mike.
It's a whole new world now.
Well, I'll hold onto it for as long as I can.
All right, good luck with that.
What do you mean?
Privacy isn't a right, it's a privilege.
You're not serious?
The U.S. Constitution contains
no expressed right to privacy.
Really?
First amendment, privacy of the home,
third amendment, privacy of the person,
fourth and fifth, privilege
against self-incrimination,
but nowhere does it say,
"You have the inalienable right to privacy."
Well, I'm talking about
all this internet stuff.
All this crap where I can't take a shit
without someone's opinion, you know?
You know, what I mean is,
I don't think it's making
anyone's life better.
Well, I guess it just depends on what
your life was to begin with, you know?
I'll be back in a jiffy.
I just gotta get something from my car.
(BEEPING)
(SIZZLING)
Well, that's just about everything.
It all should be running much
faster and smoother by now.
Good, really appreciate it, Ed.
You know Rose.
This is our daughter, Kaitlyn.
- Hi.
- KAITLYN: Hey.
Honey, this is Ed, our new IT guy.
- Nice to meet you, Ed.
- Nice to meet you, too, Rose.
MIKE: Come, relax, join us.
Well, I should probably get going,
my girlfriend...
Ah, come on, let's have a drink.
Just one. There you go.
Kaitlyn, watch the steaks.
Come on, good man.
- (GLASSES CLINKING)
- MIKE: Enjoy.
You have a beautiful home, Mike.
Beautiful payments, too.
Tell me something, did you really learn
all your stuff from the government?
- I was with the NSA.
- No shit?
- The NSA?
- ED: Yeah.
Hang on, picture of me here in Kandahar.
MIKE: Would you look at that.
Why'd you leave?
Oh, you see things, and...
I don't like talking about it.
It's crazy, what they do.
Ed, that presentation you came in
and saved the other day?
Your Omni app?
- Yeah, I signed the NDA.
- Yeah, I know, I know.
Well, when that thing goes,
I'm gonna need guys like you.
And there's great opportunities
to be had, I promise you.
So...
stick around, Ed.
I hear you, I will.
MAN: Channel 5 Weather Center just to update
you on the line of severe thunderstorms
that extends from up near Sherman
to about Denton,
then down to the north and west.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
(HOUSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BEEPING)
PATRICK:
You're in a precarious situation, Mike.
You're overextended.
MIKE: I know.
You need capital to finance the Omni project,
which is what your investors are for.
Securitized loans.
Now, if the SEC approve them,
you launch your IPO.
If they don't, you have to liquidate,
and your fleet goes to auction
for pennies on the dollar.
What does your gut say?
PATRICK: The SEC sent me
a preliminary report.
I think we're on firm ground, it's just...
they'll issue the final decision very soon.
So we're good then?
PATRICK: Unless something new
comes to light, yeah.
It won't, will it, Mike?
No.
That's everything.
- MIKE: Good morning.
- WOMAN: Good morning, Mr. Regan.
Can you put this on my desk, please?
Thank you. Good morning.
- WOMAN: Good morning, Mr. Regan.
- MIKE: I'm coming.
WOMAN: I'll do that right away.
Yeah, I'll see you at three.
- MIKE: Andy, good morning to you.
- ANDY: Hey, Mike.
- MIKE: It's all good?
- We're good.
Hot-shot here defragged it.
Your boy Ed knows his stuff.
Glad to hear it. Good man, Ed.
Thank you.
MIKE: Come on, Andy, smile.
Come on now, there you go, Andy.
(BEEPING)
(BELL CHIMING)
(ED PANTING)
- WOMAN: Yeah, really.
- (LAUGHING)
WOMAN: Yeah.
MAN: Let me show you this.
MIKE: All right, let's see
what you're looking at here.
ROSE: Are you trying to get me drunk?
Yes. Yes, I am. How did you know?
(SPRINKLER WHIRRING)
(BEEPING)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(MUSIC PLAYING IN THE BACKGROUND)
MIKE: Yep. I got it.
ED: Evening, Mike.
Ed?
What are you doing here, Ed?
Err, Kaitlyn, she... she texted me.
Well, if she did, she...
she made a mistake.
This is family friends.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry, um...
Take the wine, it's from Spain.
No thanks.
I should probably...
I should probably get going.
MIKE: Have a good night.
- Who was it?
- Nobody.
(SIGHING)
Kate, you can't invite people to dinner
without asking me or your mother first.
Are we clear?
Invite who? I didn't invite anybody.
Is everybody okay for drinks?
- Are we okay?
- WOMAN: Yeah.
(LABORED BREATHING)
- (NEW WAVE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (HEAVY BREATHING)
(SINGING ALONG TO MUSIC)
(ED SCREAMING)
(SCREAM ECHOING)
(BEEPING)
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Come on, Kaitlyn, Katie!
- ROSE: Hey.
- Katie!
- You gotta be kidding me.
- Do not make a scene.
ED: Wow, they're playing great, huh?
Right?
What are you doing here, Ed?
Oh, Kaitlyn asked me online.
Yeah.
What, you two are talking together online?
Yeah, yeah. She just said,
"Come see my team play."
Here I am.
(CHEERING AND WHISTLING)
Yeah!
MIKE: You're getting very
good at this, sweetheart.
- ROSE: You really are, honey.
- KAITLYN: Thank you.
ED: Hey, you guys did great out there.
KAITLYN: Ed!
Hey.
- ROSE: Are you hungry?
- Yeah, I'm starving.
Good, let's go get something to eat.
- Sounds great.
- (MIKE SIGHING)
Ed, this is a kind of family thing.
You know what I mean?
Sunday, dinner, that kind of thing.
- Oh, sure.
- Hey, and thanks for stopping by.
ED: See you at work. Bye, Rose.
- Kaitlyn.
- KAITLYN: Bye.
ED: Enjoy your dinner!
I don't know why
you had to be so mean to him.
- I am not being mean to him.
- He could've come.
I'm just setting boundaries, that's all.
He works for me, he's not family.
Okay, well, I think he's nice.
Yeah, and he's a lot older than you.
- He's 28, he told me.
- And you're 17.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(BEEPING)
(MOANING)
(GASPING)
(BEEPING)
(MOANING)
(SIGHING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING FROM RADIO)
(KAITLYN SIGHING)
(TV PLAYING IN BACKGROUND)
- Hey.
- ROSE: Hey.
- Something wrong?
- No, nothing.
(SIGHING)
I got the mammogram today,
you know I hate them.
I do.
But it's always fine and you're always fine.
I know.
I love you.
And I love you.
(BELL RINGING)
(STUDENTS CHATTING)
- BOY: Dare you to do it.
- KAITLYN: Oh, my God, maybe I guess.
BOY: Hey, what are you doing this weekend?
GIRL: Well what do you think?
I thought we were going to that party.
That's what I want to do. I don't
want to sit around, I want to go out.
ED: Hey!
Kaitlyn!
Ed?
Hey.
ED: Come on, jump in,
I'll give you a ride home.
KAITLYN: Hey, how do you... Where did you...
She's fine, I'm giving her a ride.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Sure, why not?
Text me later.
Bye.
Bye, later, friend-o.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING OVER RADIO)
(ED WHISTLING)
So, was that guy your boyfriend?
Sort of.
Uh-huh.
He seems a little immature for you.
We grew up together, so...
We're mostly just friends.
So you haven't had sex yet?
Wouldn't you like to know?
Your dad'd kill me.
(ED WHISTLING)
FEMALE NEWSREADER: Major stock
market indexes are higher today.
Investors are focusing on companies
that beat...
MIKE: Oh, boy-o.
...their earnings estimates.
The Lunberg 991 Washington DC index
is up one percent, a good...
MIKE: Ah, you little shit!
He's out back, go talk to him.
(KAITLYN LAUGHING)
Dad, Ed got me the new phone.
Yeah, I get 'em for practically nothing, I...
- Dude, let's have a chat.
- ED: Something, something wrong?
- You can't give my daughter a phone.
- KAITLYN: Dad!
You can't give her a ride, either.
- KAITLYN: Dad, that's so...
- MIKE: Just be quiet.
- KAITLYN: He's being nice!
- ED: She asked me to.
- KAITLYN: Why do you take his side?
- MIKE: I don't care! Okay?
What is the problem? He's trying to be nice!
- It's just a phone.
- No, it's not.
I mean, why are we even
having this conversation?
I don't know, I didn't do anything wrong.
Ed, boy-o, this isn't working for me.
- Mike, we're friends.
- No, no, no. You work for me, okay?
Actually, you know, you don't anymore.
You're out of here, all right?
Tomorrow, clear your desk out.
Mike.
- Good luck, Ed!
- ED: Mike!
MIKE: Kaitlyn! Let's have a talk here.
KAITLYN: You are unbelievable!
Every time I make a fucking
friend, you ruin it!
- MIKE: Don't swear at me!
- KAITLYN: I hate living here!
(CLOCK TICKING RAPIDLY)
(CHATTER ECHOING)
You said ten o'clock, right?
PATRICK: It's the SEC, Mike.
Relax, we're in good shape.
MIKE: Yeah, yeah.
Omni?
I'm Linda Martinez, SEC Fraud Division.
- What?
- We have an issue.
As you are no doubt aware, Mr. Regan,
under Section 4 of the SEC
Compliance Regulations,
any attempt to lobby, coerce, or collaborate
with any member of the compliance committee
will trigger an investigation and a subsequent
delay to any initial public offering.
Well, clearly it wouldn't be
in my client's best interest to...
LINDA: We have received
evidence of such collaboration.
We've also received evidence
of electronic document tampering.
Look, um...
I'm prepared to resubmit the
documents in question here and now.
LINDA: We have therefore no other choice
than to delay or suspend your application
for an initial public offering.
Delay?
By what, a couple of weeks?
- Or months.
- PATRICK: Months!
Are you fucking kidding me?
We'll be in touch. Good day.
Someone's fucking with us.
PATRICK: Oh, my God, my God!
- (ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING)
- (APPLAUDING)
I don't know.
That play was just beyond me, I'm sorry, I...
You hated every minute of it.
- Sorry, I want my two hours back.
- (LAUGHING)
- You were asleep.
- Yeah.
All right, what's wrong?
(MIKE SIGHING)
- Mike.
- MIKE: I...
Nothing.
- It's fine.
- ROSE: What?
- We had to fire that guy.
- What guy?
Ed Porter, the I.T. guy.
The one that came around to the house?
Mm-hm.
Good, he was a creep.
Well, don't worry.
He's long gone.
No, what else? There's something else.
I'm under pressure with the SEC.
We all thought it was going fine,
and it's really just going down the shitter.
- Is it gonna be okay?
- I...
I don't know.
(BEEPING)
(SONAR-LIKE BEEPING)
- ROSE: Mike.
- MIKE: Wha...
ROSE: Mike.
Wake up.
I think there's someone in the house.
- (BEEPING)
- AUTOMATED VOICE: Door opening.
MIKE: Stay there.
(DISTANT CLANGING)
(SOFT ELECTRIC BUZZING)
(BEEPING)
(HEAVY METAL MUSIC BLARING)
ROSE: Mike?
- (BEEPING)
- (HEAVY MUSIC PLAYING)
ROSE: Mike!
Come on, you piece of fucking shit!
Fuck!
- Fuck!
- (BEEPING)
Turn off!
AUTOMATED VOICE: System set.
- ROSE: What was that?
- MIKE: It's fine, everything's fine.
ROSE: No, everything's not fine!
What the fuck was that?
MIKE: Everything's fine, okay?
Back to bed, everyone, don't worry.
Kaitlyn, I'm sorry about
that craziness last night.
- You must be tired.
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
Morning.
JOAN: Mike, I've got bad news.
We've been hacked.
It looks bad.
We have software glitches
across every single aircraft.
What the f...
JOAN: I don't know what to tell you,
Mike. He got in somehow.
I already called the police.
Our sales reps are on the phones now,
calling them one at a time
and telling them to ignore the email.
That's fucking great.
MAN: It's costing us upward
of $1.2 million a day.
What about the emails,
screwing with our clients?
They were definitely
generated from our servers.
They all have our IP address.
Clients think they came from us.
Can we shut him down?
- Who?
- Porter, the guy we fired.
- MAN: I don't know.
- Who else could do this?
Yeah, but he had access, so he probably
put a bunch of back doors on the server.
- That's what I'd do.
- Look...
Look, just change everything,
the pass codes, the words.
Do what you guys do. Secure this place.
- Get it done, please!
- Okay, Mike. Let's go, guys.
All right, quiet, everybody!
- WOMAN: Come on, kids. Stay together.
- Make sure you've got everything!
Bye-bye, honey.
(DIALING TONE)
ANSWERING MACHINE:
You've reached Dr. Francis Klein.
If this is an emergency,
hang up and call 9-1-1.
Otherwise please leave
a message after the tone.
(BEEPING)
Hi, this is Rose Regan,
I'm a patient of Dr. Klein's.
Can, um...
Can you have him call me
as soon as possible, please?
It's, um...
It's about an email he just sent me.
Thank you.
(TOOTING AND BEEPING)
Would you turn that off, please?
Listen, I'd like everyone
to stay off their smart phones
and their computers for
as much as possible, okay?
- I have a paper to write.
- So write it.
KAITLYN: Fine.
Everyone in this fucking house is crazy.
(CELL PHONE CHIMING)
Doctor Klein?
Yeah, gimme a second.
Yeah, I wanted to talk to you
about the email you sent.
The pathology report?
Yes, that I tested positive
for breast cancer.
You do that?
You send that in an email, really?
KLEIN: No, I have your pathology report
right here in front of me. It's negative.
I was just gonna call you about it, Rose.
(HEAVY BREATHING) Negative, are you sure?
Yes. Negative. Please don't worry.
You're perfectly fine.
No, thank you. Thank you, Doctor.
I don't know who emailed you what,
but everything looks fine.
Rusty, you okay?
No, I'm not.
I got an email today about the mammogram
and it said that I tested
positive for breast cancer.
Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God.
- No, I'm fine, I spoke to the doctor.
- He said...
- MIKE: Are you okay?
I'm okay. He said that I'm fine.
- Are you sure?
- He's scaring me, Mike.
It had to be him.
Mike?
Fucker. I'll tear him to pieces, Rose.
I swear to God,
I'll fucking tear him to pieces.
(RAIN PATTERING)
(ED YELLING)
(PUNCHING)
Stay away from me and family, you got it?
You shouldn't fuck over your friends, Mike.
You fucking psycho. I'm not your friend.
I didn't touch your family...
yet.
- (PUNCHING)
- (GRUNTING)
You try that, I will fucking kill you.
You understand me?
Fuck you, Regan.
I spent my whole life
dealing with bullies like you.
- (GRUNTING)
- Yeah.
"Oh, he's got fucking special skills!
Let's fucking use him!"
You fucking used me, Mike.
I wonder if your clients know what a
two-faced, fucking piece of shit you are.
- (PUNCHING)
- (GRUNTING)
Tough guy, huh? Huh?
We'll see how tough you are when your
fucking planes start falling out of the sky.
Mike, I've got your whole operation
strung up like a mine field.
- Bullshit.
- You wanna find out?
- (PUNCHING)
- (GRUNTING)
You stay the fuck away
from my family, you hear me?
Stay the fuck away from my family!
(SLAPPING)
(CELL PHONE CHIMING)
- (LAUGHING AND CHATTERING)
- (PHONES RINGING AND CHIMING)
BOY: Hey, I got that video.
(KAITLYN MOANING)
I'm sorry.
I'm here, Kaitlyn,
my darling girl, I'm so sorry.
I am so sorry, child.
Listen, I tried to warn you, I did.
The pictures you take,
the things that you record,
they can be used to hurt you.
Do you understand?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Dad, I didn't... I didn't take any pictures.
I took a shower!
Okay, I didn't do any of this! That fucking
creep you let in the house, he did this!
All right, all right, Kaitlyn, that's enough.
No, Dad, this isn't my fault!
This is your fault!
Just... No, go away!
- MIKE: Kaitlyn...
- ROSE: Honey, honey?
Great! Great job, Mike.
- MIKE: Don't start.
- (DOOR CLOSING)
- ROSE: Don't start?
- MIKE: Take her home!
ROSE: Where are you going?
Mike!
(ENGINE ROARING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Let me guess, you're on your way?
I'm gonna kill you, Porter.
I am gonna fucking kill you!
Oh, bad move!
Recorded death threat, Michael.
You fucking phoned me!
Hey, Mike, you know
what I learned at the NSA?
Everybody is a liar.
The polished man with the successful business
and the perfect family.
Beautiful wife, beautiful house,
gorgeous daughter.
It's all a fucking lie.
Let's chat about darling little Kaitlyn.
Mm, Kaitlyn, Mike.
Do you think she's still a virgin?
Because, Mike, I have my doubts.
Right, Daddy?
(KAITLYN MOANING)
You little fucker.
(ED LAUGHING)
(KAITLYN MOANING)
Don't you fucking go near my daughter!
ED: Oh, they grow up so fast.
- MIKE: You fucker!
- Don't they, Michael?
Oh, Mike, c'mon. I gave her a life lesson.
You're a dead man, it's as simple as that.
You're a fucking dead man!
I'm a dead man?
Mike, I just don't think
you have it in you to kill anybody.
(BEEPING)
You just don't have that...
that le... that level of control.
MIKE: Come on, you little fucker!
I'll fucking kill you!
You're not the master of the universe, Mike.
MIKE: You're a dead man, Porter!
(SCREAMING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(METAL AND GLASS SHATTERING)
(GROANING)
So, you told the officer
the car went out of control.
He tried to kill me!
What are you gonna do?
Okay, look. The thing is, one of
my detectives was at your company,
took a bunch of statements.
Your I.T. guys were all very eager
to mention Mr. Porter by name.
Yeah, well they worked with him.
I mean, no one liked him.
And there's this SEC investigation
going on with your company.
I'd say you've got a lot
on your plate, Mr. Regan.
Yeah, meaning?
I'd hate for you to go blaming this
poor schmuck for all your problems.
Oh, so I'm the bad guy now,
is that what you're saying?
- No, I didn't say that.
- MIKE: He tried to kill me!
You have any evidence that he's
actually done any of these things,
Mr. Regan?
- MIKE: Are you all right?
- No.
You?
What did the cops say?
Are they gonna do anything?
Mike?
Nothing.
I am so sorry.
I love you, Mike.
You're the love of my fucking life,
but I don't want to hear that.
I don't want to hear sorries.
You brought that man into our house,
into our home.
I want you to sort it out.
Yeah.
Fix it.
All right?
Yeah.
Okay?
Fix it.
- I will.
- Promise?
I promise, come here.
(CELL PHONE DIALING)
(PHONE RINGING)
PETER: Hello?
MIKE: May I speak to Peter Buck, please?
PETER: Yeah, this is... this is Peter Buck.
MIKE: Peter, this is Mike Regan.
PETER: Mike, hey.
MIKE: Listen, I am sorry to call you so late.
PETER: What can I do for you, Mike?
MIKE: Peter, I need a favor.
PETER: Okay. I'm listening.
It's not just online fraud stuff, I get it.
You gotta dig deep and take care
of the problem at its source.
You need someone who can do what he does.
You're being attacked.
You have to look at the true
point of view of an attack.
You've got so many multiple weak spots.
You know, we're not
screwing around here, Mike.
You need to shut this guy down.
Mike, with a guy like this,
you can't just get rid of him, you know?
He's gonna have left time-bombs,
trip-wire emails, the whole lot.
You gotta clean it up.
You can't just, you know, disappear this guy.
We have guys, you know, we have cleaners.
You know, that's what we call them.
State Department, CIA, has different names
for them, but we call them cleaners.
Yeah, there's a... There's a guy
we use at the State Department.
He's sort of off-program.
He might, err... might be what you need.
(SIGHING)
MIKE: Peter Bu... I am Henrik.
May I have your cell phone please, Mr. Regan?
Thank you.
Your phone will function
normally in 24 hours.
(PHONE BUZZING)
Shall we get moving?
To your right.
What's gonna happen, Mom?
I don't know.
What are you doing?
HENRIK: I don't want him to see my face.
I'm back!
This is my new friend.
It's okay, it's okay.
He doesn't want Porter to see his face.
Very nice to meet you.
Yeah, thank you.
Nice to meet you.
Hi.
- HENRIK: May I?
- Go ahead.
Very beautiful prison and...
broadcast facility you've built here.
- All the house like this?
- MIKE: Uh-huh.
- Smart everywhere?
- MIKE: Yeah.
All the rooms?
Yeah.
How do we start?
We make the house dumb.
Okay, Mr. Regan, the first thing
we do is sterilize you and your family.
We need to do all we can
to scrub you from the web,
reduce your footprint
to make you a smaller target.
Miss Regan, I need everything,
it must be absolute.
We start with the house.
We need to make our enemy
deaf, dumb and blind.
Done.
(BEEPING)
HENRIK: I need you to be completely
honest with me or this doesn't work.
I'm not here to judge, Mr. Regan,
I'm here to fix your problem.
So, if you've touched a computer
in the last five years...
...I need to know when, where, and why.
This might take a while.
This fucking house.
It means nothing to me.
HENRIK: So why did you build it?
I don't know.
The only two things I care about
are sleeping in the other room.
Everything else...
is just bullshit.
What?
His name is not Ed Porter.
He was born Richard Edward
Portman, Hawthorne, California.
January 12, 1983.
Parents divorced, 1986.
He lives with his mum, moves a lot.
His father commits suicide, 1989.
He spent his teenage years
in protective custody.
His mother was abusive towards him.
How predictable.
It would explain his obsession
with you and your family.
His medical records includes
a wide range of pharmaceuticals:
Lumictil, Zoloft, Neurontin...
So... so what are we dealing with here?
A sociopath, a psychopath?
He has serious mental health issues.
Broad spectrum.
Okay, here we go.
Ah, as I suspected.
He never worked for NSA.
Wait a second, he... he showed me
a photograph of himself
with these soldiers in Kandahar.
- HENRIK: This one?
- That's the one.
Not for real.
Not a team guy.
Hired by some NSA subcontractor, 2009.
Fired for "misuse of proprietary technology."
Okay, what does that mean?
Apparently spied on female
co-workers and ex-girlfriends.
- Jesus.
- Works as an independent IT tech.
Seven, eight companies.
No job lasts more than a couple of months.
Then hired by you.
Lucky you.
Look, he's really quite sick,
but he's also a bad man, Mr. Regan.
Nice firewall, Mr. Porter.
Not so clever, not so clever.
MIKE: What is it?
Nothing on his drive.
So?
Hackers don't trust the cloud.
They operate
from peripherals, thumb drives,
air-gapped laptops.
Portable items.
- Very good news.
- Why?
We hire someone to break in and take them.
Good news, you have them in your possession,
for evidence or to destroy.
I'll do it.
Excuse me?
I'll do the break-in.
I need everything he's got on me.
You're a connected man,
Mr. Regan, we hire someone.
I'm sick and tired of
hiring people to fix my life.
That's how I got into this mess.
I'll do this myself, no debate.
Very well.
How do we get him out of there?
Good question.
She could get him out of there.
Excuse me, what time do you close tonight?
We close at 11:00.
HENRIK: I'm so sorry.
- Are you okay?
- HENRIK: Yes, sorry.
Okay. That's okay.
- MIKE: What time?
- Um, 11:00.
Eleven o'clock, thank you very much.
(SIGHING)
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
Okay, now we control her dating app.
(FOOD PROCESSOR WHIRRING)
(CELL PHONE CHIMING)
(BEEPING)
- He bought it.
- (KEYS TAPPING)
HENRIK: When you enter,
you will trigger his alarm.
I can silence it,
but it will send him a signal.
I can delay it as long as practical.
For this part, we go low tech.
Good luck.
Wait for my signal, and remember, Mr. Regan,
be careful.
Go.
In three, two,
one...
- (BANGING)
- (BEEPING)
(BEEPING STOPS)
- (ALARM BEEPING)
- Oh, shit.
Wait!
We're good. Continue.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
He's here.
(MIKE SIGHING)
As quickly as you can, Mr. Regan.
Let's go to work. Place the camera.
Okay, how's this?
Okay, good.
Go to his desk.
ED: I got here as fast as I could.
HENRIK: Do not touch the computer.
Err...
How... how are you? I'm not
actually, um, working right now.
ED: Oh, that's okay, me neither.
HENRIK: Under his desk.
I got your message.
- Message?
- ED: Yeah, yeah.
MIKE: There's nothing. There's nothing here.
They could be anywhere. There's nothing here.
HENRIK: It will be in the room.
Look around you.
There's just some fucking toy-type thing.
He doesn't have toys.
- That's it.
- MIKE: What? It's a fucking toy.
HENRIK: Pull it apart.
- Take it apart, Mike.
- MIKE: Ah, damn it! Come on.
HENRIK: We have to move quickly, Mr. Regan.
Hey, where's my phone?
Where is it? Where is my phone?
MIKE: I got it.
Okay, that's one.
BARISTA: Seriously, I can't find it.
MIKE: That's two.
Wait, did you take my phone?
No, I didn't take your phone.
Someone's been playing games.
Oh, shit.
You must hurry.
Just leave it, abort.
Sixty seconds.
MIKE: Damn it, come on!
HENRIK: We're burned. He's on the move.
Abort!
- MIKE: I got them all.
- HENRIK: Grab what you can.
He's moving.
Now or never.
- Forty seconds.
- I'm almost there.
- That's it, I got them all.
- Five seconds.
HENRIK: Get out now!
- He has a gun.
- MIKE: What? Where is he?
HENRIK: Okay, wait.
WOMAN: Can you confirm you're going to the...
In the building.
We got an officer down inside,
Division Eight, Battalion One,
on a shooting...
14300 East Alameda Avenue.
HENRIK: I see him.
Do exactly as I say.
I'll tell you when to move.
(ALARM BEEPING)
Step into the hall.
Wait.
Go.
Your left.
The fire escape, next floor up. Go!
- (LOUD FOOTSTEPS)
- (SIRENS BLARING)
ED: Hey!
- (BULLET WHIZZING)
- (MIKE GRUNTING)
ED: You motherfucker!
MIKE: I got them, I got them.
Okay, let's go! Come on.
COP 1: Freeze, on your knees!
COP 2: Don't move! Put the gun down, now!
- I have a permit!
- COP 2: Drop the fucking weapon!
- ED: I have a permit.
- COP 2: Put it down!
HENRIK: Oh, shit.
(RADIO CHATTERING)
ED: Look, officers, my permit's
in order, I just... I need it.
There's this guy...
COP: What guy?
This guy, I used to work for him...
- He's been stalking me.
- COP: You can't shoot him.
I won't.
COP: You got a problem, then you come to us.
Okay.
- COP: All right?
- All right.
COP: What do you need a gun for?
You come to us, and we'll sort it out.
Edward?
I just... I just need it.
You know, I've been fucking scared.
I just don't know where else to turn.
COP: You come to us and we'll sort it out.
Yeah.
COP: Now I'm gonna
give you this gun, tonight,
- at the station.
- Okay.
COP: After you calm down.
Thank you.
- (STATIC PLAYING)
- (CRASHING)
- (EXHALING)
- (PHONE RINGING)
OPERATOR: 9-1-1, where is your emergency?
9-1-1, what is your emergency?
Hello, operator?
- OPERATOR: Sir.
- Hello
My name is Edward Porter.
(SOBBING) I'd like to report a...
Yes, I've been attacked.
OPERATOR: Tell me
what's wrong with you, okay?
It's, it's a, what do you
call it, it's a home invasion.
OPERATOR: All right,
I need you to stay calm, okay?
(SOBBING) I don't know if he's still here.
I'm hurt pretty bad, can you please come?
422 147th Street.
- OPERATOR: I have...
- ED: Please come, please!
OPERATOR: I have someone coming to you.
(PHONE CLATTERING ON FLOOR)
(PHONE RINGING)
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
(THUDDING)
Good luck, Mr. Regan,
with the rest of it.
Thanks.
(FOOTSTEPS)
- (SQUEAKING)
- (THUDDING)
(POLICE RADIO CHATTERING)
(PHONE RINGING)
It's all there.
All his programs.
All the information he gathered on me.
Everything he used to try and wreck my life.
It's all there, everything.
Have your lab look at it.
- (PHONE RINGING)
- (POLICE RADIO CHATTERING)
How did you get these?
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- MAN: Jim, can I see you for a minute?
What's up?
MAN: Nah, I just need to see you
for a minute.
Yeah, sure.
MAN: Thanks.
I'll be back, Mr. Regan.
OFFICER: What, Mike Regan over there?
Are you kidding? Huh?
What are we gonna do about it?
Well, I mean, evidence is...
All right. You gonna do it?
All right.
- OFFICER: Stand up, please.
- Michael Regan, you are under arrest
for burglary and aggravated assault.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say may be used against you.
You have the right to have any attorney
present when being questioned.
If you can't afford an attorney,
one will be appointed to you
by the court of law of the city of Baltimore.
Do you understand and hear these rights?
That's him, right there!
Right there, that's him!
- Keep walking.
- MIKE: You motherfucker!
- VOICEOVER: Hey, hey!
- MIKE: I see you, Porter!
Don't let him go, don't let him fucking walk!
Come on, take him out of here!
Hey, Porter! You shit bag, Porter!
You fucking motherfucker, that's him!
- Take it easy.
- MIKE: I'll fuckin' kill ya!
(KAITLYN SNIFFING)
He's, um... Dad's in jail, right?
Hey, hey. (KISSING)
- Dad's gonna be okay.
- (SOBBING)
Honey, he didn't do anything wrong.
- Sir.
- DETECTIVE: Can I help you?
I was wondering if,
um, I could perhaps
have my thumb drives back?
They're evidence.
You can have them back when our lab says so.
I also had a legally held firearm.
DETECTIVE: That you can have.
See the desk sergeant on the way out.
Good night.
Thank you, sir. Goodnight.
MIKE: You're the I.T. guy, right?
ED: Yeah, that's right, Ed Porter.
MIKE: Yeah, Mike Regan, you really
saved my ass in there today, thanks.
This is my daughter, Kaitlyn, you know Rose.
ED: Stick around.
MIKE: You fucking psycho,
I am not your friend.
Listen to me, I will fucking kill you!
(PHONE BEEPING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Rose?
(KNIFE BLADE SWISHING)
Who's there?
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED WHIMPERING)
ED: Nobody.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Drop the knife, Mike.
(MUFFLED WHIMPERING)
(KNIFE CLATTERING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
They look perfect, don't they? Hm?
- Tough guy?
- Oh!
(MUFFLED WHIMPERING)
Come on, sit up straight.
Sit up straight.
Sit up straight!
- (GUNSHOT BOOMING)
- (MUFFLED SCREAMING)
- (GLASS SHATTERING)
- (MUFFLED SOBBING)
(MIKE GROANING)
Ed.
(ED LAUGHING)
ED: So, here we are, all together now.
Let's play happy families, let's sing a song.
Then maybe I kill everyone in the room.
Rose, shoulders back.
(MUFFLED CURSING)
Come on, Rose.
Is this what you want?
Is this what you want, is that what you want?
I'm not scared of you any more, Mike.
I don't like you any more, Mike.
(MUFFLED WHIMPERING)
ED: # No one listens any more #
# When no one listens, what are words for #
# When no one listens #
# No one's listening #
(GUN CLICKING)
# At all #
(ED LAUGHING)
(MIKE YELLING)
- (GUNSHOT BOOMING)
- (GLASS SHATTERING)
- (WIND HOWLING)
- (MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Mike, Mike.
(FISTS THUDDING)
Mike!
- (FISTS THUDDING)
- (GRUNTING AND YELLING)
(MUFFLED YELLING)
(THUDDING)
(MIKE YELLING)
(FISTS THUDDING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
ROSE: Mike.
Mike!
(GUN CLICKING)
Please.
Don't.
ROSE: Mike?
Mike!
Mike, please, don't.
For god's sake!
Don't kill him!
Please, don't kill him!
Honey, please.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(APPLAUDING)
(DREAMY TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING)